啊！
冇，多謝。
歡迎啊，楊局長。
請問各位委員對上述安排有冇意見？
下次會議討論嘅事項咧，就包括。
委員，我哋夠鍾又夠人嚇，噉啊可以開會啦。
香港銀行費用規例第四百四廿八D章及。
民航飛機噪音證明規例第三百一十二A章。
系統啟用前嘅準備工作，同埋應對突發事故嘅機制。
空運航空服務牌照規例第四百四十八A章嘅費用同收費。
同交通事務委員會主席陳恆鑌議員商量之後咧，我哋會邀請。
交通事務委員會出席下次嘅例會，即係成為一個聯席會議啦，討論國際機場三包。
咁另外咧就係香港機場跑道第三跑系統啟用前嘅準備工作，同埋應對突發事故嘅機制。
噉啊！議程第一項，上次會議發出資料文件咧，就有三份資料文件，詳情已經再列喺議程第一項。
噉啊，跟住議程第三項咧，就係香港迪士尼園度假區最新嘅進度報告啦。噉我哋請官員同埋迪士尼園嘅代表出席。
喺待議事項第一覽表嘅第一項同第二項。此外咧，我哋收到張欣宇議議員嘅來函咧，要求我哋同交通事務委員會召開聯席會議，討論國際機場近期嘅事故。啊，經過同政府當局聯繫同埋。
啊，審專員嚇，各位，嗯。
Welcome, Mr Moriarty. Welcome. Yeah, thank you.
咧，亦都教香港整體旅客訪港人次為佳，帶動全年入場人次咧係按年上升百分之八十七，去到六百四十萬。
香港迪士尼係香港其中一個好重要嘅旅遊景點。除咗提升香港對區內旅客嘅吸引力，多年嚟咧，其實亦都為本港帶嚟可觀嘅經濟收益。
第二總收入按年咧係飆升一百五十六個percent，喺扣除利息、税項、折舊同埋攤銷之後嘅淨虧損咧，亦都按年大幅改善啦，百分之八十三。
上香港迪士尼能夠喺疫情之後迅速轉虧為盈，亦都有強勁嘅業務勢頭咧，係對香港旅遊業發展嘅一個好大嘅鼓舞。香港迪士尼嘅行政總裁莫偉瑩先生咧，稍後會更加仔細咁同大家介紹。
喺推旅遊推廣同埋吸引旅客訪港方面咧，係持續緊密合作。誒，我而家咧請阿Michael咧同大家介紹一下香港迪士尼嘅營運情況，然後咧我哋會回答委員嘅問題。阿Michael，offert to you please。Mr. Moriarty，your turn。
推動文化、娛樂、體育同埋旅遊嘅融合工作，例如剛剛喺一月舉行咗一場迪士尼經典音樂live朗朗誒領銜演奏，之後喺四月同埋五月咧，同香港芭蕾舞蹈團咧係繼續展出合。
嚇！多謝政府同迪士尼園嘅代表出席。首先，局長係咪你介紹下？嚇！嗯，首先同大家簡介一下啦。嗱，各位等一陣字禁制嚇，我個同各位講禁制字禁啦嚇，唔該曬。好啊，誒，同大家簡介一下香港迪士尼喺二零二。
三財政年度，即係由二零二二年嘅十月初去到二零二三年九月底嘅營運情況。香港迪士尼咧喺二零二三財政年度嘅頭五個月，即係由二零二二年嘅十月咧去到二零二三年嘅二月咧嘅經營環境咧，嗰陣時係仍然受到疫情嘅影響，但係隨住跨境。
旅遊咧喺二零二三年二月開始復常，香港旅遊業亦都開始全速復甦。香港迪士尼嘅營運表現強勁，綜合整個財政年度嘅表現咧，第一樣本地入人本地入場人次咧係再創新高，加上非本地入場人次嘅復甦情況。
值得留意嘅咧，係由於香港迪士尼嘅財政年度咧係截至每年嘅九月底，因此今次彙報嘅二零二三財政年度嘅數字咧，係未能反充分反映香港迪士尼喺跨境旅遊復甦之後，特別係舊年去年十一月全球首個《魔雪奇緣》世界開幕後嘅。
嘅業務表現，上星期香港迪士尼已經宣佈，如單以二零二三歷年分析，即係話喺二零二三成年去分析咧，香港迪士尼全年已經錄得順利。而令二零二四年一月至三月嘅按季收入同埋淨利潤咧，亦都創開元以嚟嘅紀錄。事實。
誒累計嘅增值增加值咧，係達到一千二百九十六億港元，亦都帶嚟咗大量嘅就業機會，培育款待工程、創意同埋設計等多個領域嘅專才。與此同時，香港迪士尼咧亦都致力服務本地嘅社羣。我我亦都特別欣惜咧，香港迪士尼致力。
一合作一個推出Stellar Lou夢想起舞吧嘅表演，亦都將會喺今年十一月咧係舉行10K Weekend 2024，更加首度加入喺全新魔雪奇緣世界裏邊唱跑嘅新體驗。政府對香港迪士尼未來嘅業務發展同埋長期嘅發展潛力咧，係充滿。
信心。展望未來，我哋期望香港迪士尼咧會鞏固其作為香港標誌性同埋地標性旅遊景點嘅角色，繼續推出新嘅節目同埋活動，包括有序推展跨年擴建同埋發展計劃嘅餘下項目，亦都為賓客咧係帶嚟更高質量嘅體驗，亦都同旅遊業界咧嘅夥伴咧。
多謝，主席。
The world of frozen, without a doubt, has further supported our success.
Not only have we emerged from COVID triumphant, but we have turned the corner financially.
And most recently, World of Frozen, we have become a drawcard for Hong Kong tourists.
作為我提到，我們開始看到一個快速的恢復，作為一啲旅行限制被解除。
Our guests returned with a newfound excitement, and our business momentum has been positive ever since.
and the love of the frozen franchise around the world and in Asia has kept our momentum growing even higher.
As you may know already, during calendar year 2023, Hong Kong Disneyland Resort turned profitable.
While local attendance remains strong, all the unique offerings and strategies we put in place during COVID have given us a boost to our non-local attendance.
And the strong momentum continues. The first quarter of 2024 was our most successful quarter ever, achieving record levels of revenue, EBITDA and net income.
The orange line shows Hong Kong Disneyland's rebound in non-local attendance, while the green line represents the recovery in total visitor arrivals to Hong Kong as compared to 2018 levels.
Through a series of record-breaking achievements fuelled by creativity and innovation, including a new signature offerings, including the reimagined Castle of Magical Dreams, our nighttime spectacular Momentus.
這些紀錄不是結果只有一樣，然而，它們是我們驚人的演員、品牌的力量，所有結合來提供驚人的體驗和創造持久的回憶給我們的客人。
According to a Hong Kong Tourism Board survey, Hong Kong Disneyland Resort is the number one paid attraction in Hong Kong among overnight visitors, and the third overall tourist destination, only behind TST and the Peak in two thousand and twenty-three.
你可見到，自2023年3月，我們享有一個加劇的復甦，而我們的總體復甦仍維持在市場之上，即使在《世界之凍》發行之前，以及2023年。
We have entered a new era for Hong Kong Disneyland, and I am extremely proud of all that we've accomplished in the lead-up to our 20th anniversary, achieving profitability in the calendar year 23, and our rebound in visitors outpacing the overall Hong Kong tourism market.
also，according to the same survey，among our visitors。
我們也 posted double-digit growth in guest spending when compared to pre-COVID levels.
52% said that Hong Kong Disneyland is their main reason for coming to Hong Kong.
We are a part of the community we live and work in by collaborating with NGOs to make a difference right here.
And in 2023, the resort welcomed its 100 millionth guest since opening.
Our guest spending has significantly improved, with in-park spending growing up to fifty-four percent compared to prior year.
And last year, we provided more than 100,000 complimentary theme park tickets to underserved communities.
We saw a strong rebound among our non-local guests too, particularly those from mainland China in the second half of the year.
Our Disney volunteers have contributed nearly 120,000 hours, delivering happiness, support and comfort to the community.
And we're more than just a driver for tourism. We're a major economic driver, job creator, and become a part of the social fabric of Hong Kong.
over overall attendance grew 87% to 6.4 million, and total hotel utilisation for the year was 77%.
在 terms of job creation, the resort has created over 290,000 jobs cumulatively, and as of right now, we have over 9,000 cast members.
The growth is driven by our strategies delivered over the past few years, bringing elegant and sophisticated products that are elevating and completing our guest experience.
在 terms of economic impact over the past 18 years, total direct and indirect value generated by Hong Kong Disneyland amounted to nearly 130 billion dollars.
在 fiscal twenty three， Hong Kong Disneyland delivered a solid financial performance across the board with strong growth compared to the prior year， despite the lingering effects of the pandemic。
Local guest affinity for the resort continued to grow. With fiscal 23, we enjoyed historic high local attendance, including a record high attendance among young adults and students from the Disney Youth Program.
這些 shows 增強了兩者整體的公園體驗和品牌形象。
Our guests are spending more, and the vast majority, over 90%, are saying their Disney experience is good value for money.
你可見到，我們轉了身，並成為盈利的，在第二個財政年度，即係從四月到九月。
We also joined forces with local art and cultural groups, bringing the best of Disney and local talents to our guests.
我們也 champion champion sports development by rolling out youth sports training initiatives and supporting those in need.
我們 proud to say that this year the magical run will be running through the kingdom of Arendelle for the first time.
And once free of COVID restrictions, we've resumed our large-scale community service programmes. We supported the Strive and Rise programme and many other NGOs.
作為我之前提到，我們在曆年2023年是盈利的，而這張圖表顯示，財年其實是關於前後COVID的。
We are also big supporters of Hong Kong's sports development. Our flagship mega event, Disney's 10K Weekend, is popular not only among locals but visitors from around the region.
As part of our commitment to nurture talent in the area, our signature annual design competition, the Disney Imagination's Design Competition, was extended to youth in the Greater Bay Area this year.
在 addition to profitability， another key milestone is that the resort has fully repaid the revolver facility funded by the Walt Disney Company in December and has not drawn on it since.
and as I mentioned to you before, Q1 24 was a record quarter, and the launch of the world's first and largest world of frozen has contributed to fuel our positive business momentum and profitability.
We have established a new Christmas holiday tradition in recent years with Disney Live and concert series, and for the first time, we collaborated with world famous pianist Lang Lang and a talented string quartet for an exclusive show in front of our beautiful castle.
Over the past few years, our partnerships have spanned across the Hong Kong Philharmonic Orchestra, Hong Kong Ballet, Hong Kong's Children Choir, and many top local talents. Our collaboration with the Academy of Performing Arts has also grown from strength to strength.
所以，Despite the impact of the pandemic during fiscal 23， our revenue grew 156% to 5.7 billion， EBITDA improved 207% to 924 million， and we closed the gap on net loss by 83% to 356 million.
As you can see here, the world of Frozen represents our finest example of exceptional storytelling that Disney is known for. It is rich with captivating stories, state-of-the-art technology, beloved characters like Anna, Elsa and Olaf, and of course, the enchanting music and the unique Hong Kong landscape.
嗯。
李慧宏。
環境保護也是我們工作的一部分。
就冇十五個，呢十六。
在March， we held our first ever service celebration to recognise these cast members.
哦，周浩鼎嚇，啊，每人四分鐘。而家林少魯議員先。誒，多謝主席。
inclusion is a value that goes back to Walt Disney's core philosophy when he first dreamed up the idea for Disneyland.
十六啊嚇！嗯嗯，各位每人四分鐘，就周文講啊，已經喺度啦。
Hong Kong Disneyland Resort is already home to the largest single solar panel site in Hong Kong, and we are continuing to grow.
The resort also joined hands with local hospitals, bringing hope and happiness to young patients with a Disney touch.
all of this, the milestones, the achievements, the community work cannot happen without the support of our amazing cast members.
We feel lucky to work with the the best team in the business, and get to create magical moments like these for our guests and for each other every day.
As champions of that vision, we work with NGOs to bring sign language and theatrical interpretation into our highly popular shows, and scholarships to young artists with disabilities.
since opening in two thousand and five, we have remained one of Hong Kong's largest employers in the tourism and entertainment industry. In fact, more than two thousand of our cast members have been with us for more than ten years.
again，我 want to thank all the members for their support through the years. As we enter our twenty-th anniversary next year, we look forward to shining even brighter as Hong Kong's beacon of tourism. Thank you, Madam Chair. Thank you. 哥位可以撳掣啦。
摩耶契。
anything to add, Mr Moriarty?
Provides us with a lot of optimism for for the future.
係誒一啲個營運數字上邊咧，就我想睇睇咧。嗱誒，如果我哋睇翻嗰個流動資產咧。
產誒收益同埋股東權益嗰方面嘅一個估算咧，咁或者係嗰個誒願景係如何咧？咁多謝主席。
誒其實誒喺如果我哋睇翻個歷史嘅發展過程，咁十年咁計，二零一四年咁去到一九年咁二五年咧喺個上升軌嗰度。
相信即係暫時嚟講，我哋都有信心佢今年個個會做得好嘅。噉佢做得好嘅時候，希望嚇即係嗰個數字慢慢會有盈餘嘅時候，嗰個股東權益可以增加翻。誒，或者我睇下樂園嗰邊會唔會有嘢補充嚇。
誒股東權益亦都喺個上升軌嗰度，噉啊二零一九之後咧，依五年咧就落入咗個下降軌嚇，噉啊流動資產雖然係稍為好翻少少啫，由九百七十二誒唔係九。
非常踴躍啊！噉我讀一次先啦嚇。林少魯議員、何敬康、林建峯、江玉歡、陳祖恆、梁希、周文港、陳少雄、田北慎、容海欣、李子敬、陸仲雄、嚴江、姚柏良、李。
就誒，首先恭喜迪士尼樂園啦，即係基本上喺過去一年都能夠即係有一個好明顯嘅嘅業務上邊嘅反彈咧噉樣，咁依個係誒值得開心嘅。咁但係無論如何，因為始終都係蝕緊錢嚇，噉啊依個都係老問題。噉我想針對咧就係。
九億七千二去翻十億，誒十一億唔夠噉樣。咁但係個股東缺唔益嗰方面嚟講咧，我暫時睇唔到有一個即係向翻上升嗰個趨勢喺度。噉我問題咧就係其實有冇一個未來五年嘅一個大概喺流動資產？
誒主席或者我講兩句先，就請啊啊，即係樂園嗰邊去講一講啦。我諗我諗過去嗰幾年，大家會見到誒嗰個誒一一九年之後嘅情況，主要都係因為疫情啦。噉你當你誒冇一個誒入即係入樂園嘅人數嘅時候，如果如
大部分係本地嘅時候，本地嘅嘅旅客當然即係本地入園參去玩嘅人，當然佢嘅消費會比係旅客入嚟係會少一啲啦。咁自然佢嗰個誒即係嗰個收入嗰年就會蝕錢咧，或者唔能夠誒賺到錢。當佢蝕錢嘅時候，你個股東嘅權益一定會跟住降嘅，因為。
何敬康議員。
我覺得係善心 person。
The other thing that I'm also very interested in is the
The next five years, and also debt repayment and dividend plans.
In recovering from a tourism standpoint, I think we look at it as a tailwind right now, and that Hong Kong will recover.
Are there going to be any synergies to work with Disney Cruise to either bring cruise members on board to Hong Kong as well as other kind of synergy plans with Hong Kong Disneyland?
You tell me the revenue breakdown between Frozen and all the other older attractions, and how do you see the older attraction perform in the next few years? Given that Frozen is going to take the lead.
都有同誒即係唔同嘅遊輪公司去傾嘅，咁當然誒所有對香港發展有利嘅，我哋都希望可以誒帶到落嚟，咁誒呢啲討論我哋會繼續落去嚇。嗯，Mr Moriarty。
如果唔係你嗰個，你嗰個就誒會會誒，即係平衡唔到噉，所以呢個都係因為嗰個疫情嘅情況咧，類似有呢個噉嘅情況出現。咁即係話，大家都會見到誒樂園嗰邊已經講咗喺今年二零二四年嚇第一季，佢哋都會係最好嘅一季嘅時候咧。噉我相。
Thank you, Madam Chair. Yes, as you mentioned, 2014 to 2019 were upward trends in terms of liquidity, which has been very helpful. I think even now, as we emerge from from COVID, we're very happy with the trajectory and the momentum that we're seeing right now. As we mentioned before during the
在第二半個財政年，我們是正向，貢獻到正向累積虧損，在那期間。但係，亦都，我們現在所見到嘅係，繼續出軌香港整體旅遊業嘅復甦。我認為，呢個結合咗我們持續嘅動力同盈利，同Frozen。
主席，冇一個簡單嘅跟進咧，即係雖然佢冇答到我，即係未有冇未來五年嘅一啲嘅估算咧。咁但係誒，或者我反翻轉頭嚟問，即係從營運個角度嚟講，喺未來一段日子有睇唔睇到一啲咩特別嘅負面因素，尚喺業會裡面同我哋分享嘅咧，多謝主席。喺樂園嗰邊，Mr.
Madam Chair, when we visit the markets, whether it be Southeast Asia, mainland or North Asia, we see very positive signs for Hong Kong's tourism. I think that the overall recovery is very much tied to travel to Hong Kong, whether it be air flight capacity.
或what we've seen positively in terms of cross boundary traffic in the GBA area, with greater access points, high speed rail, the the bridge of course, all providing positive benefits. So I think that you know where Hong Kong might be slower than other markets.
Madam President, I got a few questions, so I'm going to dig right into it. I'm very excited that Hong Kong Disneyland has recorded a very good first quarter 2024, having record new net income, EBITDA and revenue, largely attributable to the world of Frozen. Could
Okay. Good. Thank you.
咁會唔會誒短期內翻嚟咧？
林建峯議員，咁都係主席。
咁最後一方面咧，就係啊。
誒好高興見到迪士尼園啦，就開始轉虧為盈。
氣候暖化，千祈唔好啊！保持唔到依個温度，溶解咗佢。
which will also have product within it, and the shareholders are in discussions for additional attractions between Marvel and the twenty-th anniversary.
香港一啲招商引資啊，啊總部遷嚟香港啊，多啲人嚟香港長住啊，噉我覺得依啲對樂樂園嗰個啊attendance都有好大幫助嘅。
嗱，我哋睇到舊年十一月咧，依個新樂園區Frozen開始咗之後咧，就旅客多咗好多。咁當然Frozen咧就係其中一個啊有有佢吸引力嘅園區嚟啦。咁但係我哋都都要小心啲，因為而家全球。
The other thing is that could you also give us a teaser about expansion plans in terms of upcoming attractions? Another thing is that I can see that per capita spending has increased significantly year on year. What are the plans to further increase per
Capital spending in the next few years, and could you also tell me the breakdown between local tourist, mainland tourists from mainland China as well as international tourists, and also give us a financial outlook.
Disney Cruise，that we all know that Singapore landed the Disney Cruise and has signed a five year contract with the Singapore government. And the question back to Secretary Young is that are there any plans to get it back in two in in five years time? Number one. Number two is that having said that during these five years.
誒誒，主席或者我先答咗嗰個誒遊輪嗰個part先，因為其他數字我交畀樂園嗰邊答。誒遊輪嗰邊點解誒我哋會答咧？因為誒其實管理公司嗰邊咧，主要係負責樂園嘅運作啦。咁喺嗰個遊輪，即係迪士尼遊輪嗰邊咧，係即係喺成個集團裏邊係另外一部分。噉我哋一路。
Thank you, Madam Chair. As it relates to the overall revenue for the world of frozen, I think it's important to recall that our recovery started to outpace the market as soon as travel restrictions were removed, and we became profitable even before the world of frozen was opened up. Certainly, the world of frozen has.
Added to and contributed to continuing momentum going forward, as well as profitability. As it relates to the specific breakdown of revenue, as you know, we have one ticket price every day for our guests, and it's not necessarily broken down by frozen. That being said, frozen has had a significant
significant impact on our park and it continues to do so. As it relates to expansion, you might recall that Frozen was just one part of a multi-year expansion that the shareholders had agreed to and lawmakers here had approved, including Moana, Ant-Man and the Wasp.
The Castle of Magical Dreams, Follow Your Dreams Daytime Show, The Nighttime Spectacular, Momentous, World of Frozen, and of course Marvel. The shareholders are already working on the Marvel expansion. Not only that, but we are focused on our twenty-th anniversary coming up.
咁過去幾年咧，實際上經營一個樂園咧，係一啲都唔容易嘅。疫情嘅關係啦，啊少人嚟咗香港嘅關係啦。噉我哋睇到咧，而家內地嘅旅客咧，一步一步咧就多多啲嚟香港啦。咁亦都香港一啲政策咧，對我哋。
估㗎。
Mr. Moriarty。
yes，Madam Chair。
和 hire the best talent here in Hong Kong.
咁誒，可可唔可以講一講個前景？誒，個Foshan個園區之後，你哋有啲咩計劃？點樣保持依個聲勢，繼續賺錢咧？
外邊嘅遊客啦，噉我想請問下局長，會有冇一啲加大宣傳嘅功夫或者嘅計劃會再做咧嚇，增大嗰個即係外邊嘅遊客比例咧？唔該，主席。
What we're doing for the twenty-th anniversary and a new attraction in between that that we're in discussions with the shareholders about. I think all of those you know put together really you know provide a significant draw to Hong Kong, and I think really will help Hong Kong tourism for a number of years now.
江玉歡議員咯，多謝主席。誒，我好高興見到咧迪士尼嘅財政表現咧有一個好顯著嘅進步，亦都喺最近呢幾個月創出咗紀錄。噉啊，迪士尼確實咧係為我哋嘅就業啦、税收啊，同埋我哋嘅香港嘅形象咧，我相信都係好有貢獻嘅。
咁但係喺呢個Frozen嘅新區之餘咧，我哋睇到日本咧，除咗Frozen咧，佢仲有兩個啊新區㗎，即係將會係開設㗎。噉我哋喺喺香港跟住落嚟有啲咩計劃咧嚟到保持呢個聲勢咧，或者保持呢個吸引力咧？我覺得誒。
即係我哋大家都想知道嘅。咁另外咧，就響保持嗰個質素嚇，同埋嗰個人手誒落落完嘅人手嗰方面咧，我覺得我哋都係關注嘅。因為香港而家咧，周圍都係搶人才，係嘛？我哋嗰啲會唔會畀人搶住咧？新加坡搶起我哋嗰啲去啦～
誒Michael亦都介紹過啦，有關你哋回饋社會，譬如招呼一啲有需要嘅團體啊、人士啊，噉我哋好高興㗎。我哋希望咧，你響賺錢賺錢之後咧，會繼續做多一啲噉嘅嘢，因為香港實際上有好多有需要嘅人士係需要我哋去照。
As it relates to our expansion, I think there's several levels that we approach. First of all, our special events throughout the year provide something new for guests, really every day and every season. I think this summer's Pixar celebration is a fine example of that, leveraging the popular intellectual property coming out of Inside Out.
And of course, you may have heard that Inside Out is the most popular animated film this summer. In fact, it reached a billion US dollars in box office in just 19 days, the fastest of any animated film. And we'll keep refreshing those special events. But again, as I mentioned.
Earlier, we have a pretty significant expansion during COVID, which many of the guests have not been able in our target markets have not been able to see yet, and so that is also a powerful drawcard for us right now. Also, I think we're very much excited about the Marvel expansion.
As it relates to manpower, very quickly, I think we're very proud to say that we are one of the most popular employers in Hong Kong and we've been first in line in many hiring situations. That being said, the market is very challenging and we're looking at a variety of ways to make sure we retain.
噉啊！我有三條問題。第一咧，誒嗱，其實我哋頭先有幾位同事都有講過啊，可唔可以擴充咧？咁嚇噉，我想請問一下咧，譬如可能阿局長可以即係畀啲啟示我哋，譬如喺空間上面有冇機會真係畀佢哋擴充咧？因為如果要做園區咧，都係要土地嘅。香港咧就。
Mr. Moriarty.
只有請樂園嗰邊得嚇。啊，Mr. Moriuchi。
係，多謝主席。咁誒，首先亦都係誒。
有冇跟進啊？工業冇啦，唔跟住先。咁跟住陳祖恆議員。
我亦都會誒考慮或者參考下，能夠可以有啲誒多多元化啲嘅旅遊咧，唔該。
I think this late in the fiscal year, I think we're we're confident in our position and how we're going to finish this this year.
主席，Thank you very much. As it relates to expansion right now, the world of frozen, you know, clearly.
就得三百一十公頃咧，迪士尼。如果比對最近嘅東京咧，都有四百九十四嘅公頃嘅地，咁會唔會真係有一啲空間畀佢哋第日再擴展咧？咁第二咧就係喺誒業績方面咧嗱，我知道業績咧有好大嘅改善，但係仍然有一個淨嘅虧損。咁誒，我想問下咧。
譬如迪士尼方面，會唔會去到預計一下未來一年啦？嗰個會唔會真係會有顯著一啲淨嘅利潤咧？嚇，嗰個即係個projection會係點咧？最後一條問題就關於遊客嘅比例嗱，我見到本地嘅遊客咧都係佔咗一個好大嘅比例，跟住就到外地嘅遊客即係。
誒都係主席就誒，我唞一答，即係第一同第三條啦。誒做嗰個宣傳咧，其實我哋同迪士尼係一齊做嘅，即係我哋喺誒旅發局嗰邊咧，其實亦都係即係喺對外宣傳，唔單止當內地啦，喺外地宣傳、東南亞宣傳咧。誒，其實都會。
佢同誒會宣傳迪士尼，即係譬如嗰陣時誒Frozen出嘅時候，大家一齊合作啦。咁當然迪士尼自己本身亦都好熱衷喺佢嘅即係目標市場裏邊做好多宣傳嘅工作啦。咁呢個所以誒，我哋會繼續做落去，吸引多啲即係內地又好或者外地又好，都係吸引佢哋多啲嚟呢度。
空間擴充嗰度咧，其實誒喺迪士尼附近咧係有啲土地喺度嘅。咁當然即係誒到時究竟我哋係咪應該擴充或者應該點做咧？誒，我哋當然第一會同迪士尼繼續去傾啦。第二亦都要睇翻成個土地用途究竟點樣係最適合咧，因為我哋都係當用到。
嗰啲土地嘅時候，我哋當然都係以即係成個香港嘅整體利益去考慮啦。咁誒，但係目前嚟講咧，誒喺迪士尼附近係有一啲土地喺度，係暫時未有一個好明明顯或者已經劃咗嘅規劃嘅用途喺度。咁誒，至於中間嗰條，我或者請誒樂園嗰邊答嚇。
Thank you, Madam Chair. I'll take the second question with respect to our confidence for 2024's fiscal results. As we discussed, first quarter this year was a record quarter for us, and our momentum, both in terms of revenue and profitability, continue to to go on. I
恭喜誒！我哋迪士尼啦，今次誒今年我哋嘅誒財政嘅表現，同埋誒叫做誒旅客等等嘅表現都做得非常之好。咁誒，我哋唔需要再咁擔心啦。而家關於嗰個叫做誒財政嘅赤字，噉我諗正面啲去睇咧，就希望能夠可以去睇遠啲。
睇翻我哋點樣去提謀嗰個發展啦。嗯，最近我哋都不斷喺度睇緊，就係我哋旅遊嘅發展嘅二點零。噉我都想睇遠少少。咁從迪士尼嘅發展，我都明白，因為我哋香港整體嗰個地嘅一個問題咧，即係未必能夠做到咁大。但係我諗我關注嘅可能係關於譬如誒。
亦都係喺前海。
香港最好咧，作為一個依歸嚇。
looking at you know market conditions and any opportunity to expand and provide capacity in that way.
個局長，相唔相答？有論先啊！我我答咗先啦。誒，其實我哋已經接觸過嘅啦，即係簡單嚟講嚇。噉我哋會繼續討論。咁誒誒。
考慮去擴建咧，有冇考慮過咧？咁呢個係畀誒迪士尼去考慮嘅問題同埋回答嘅問題。另外想請問楊局長咧，會唔會考慮喺今年去接觸迪士尼，去問下佢哋嘅遊輪明年可唔可以增加一啲站點喺香港咧？唔該曬，主席，多謝曬。
overall tourism and the strategy of Hong Kong's tourism 2.0. As it relates to tourism 2.0, Hong Kong Disneyland is poised and ready to contribute in any way, you know, to the success of tourism in Hong Kong. Hong Kong success is Hong Kong Disneyland's success.
遊樂設施嘅數量啦，咁可能我哋未必塊地咁大，但係我哋可以劈得好啲。噉我都想聽聽，譬如話嚟緊呢幾年嘅增加嘅一個方向，有啲可能已經落實，有啲可能規劃。想聽聽誒迪士尼嗰邊或者國長嗰邊誒，可以同我哋分享下。咁同埋人數嘅上限之後，我哋叫capacity building啦。
咁人數上限嗰度一路上嘅時候，我都希望能夠可以隨住我哋預計我哋嘅旅客嘅增長嘅時候咧，亦都可以將我哋整體成個迪士尼做大佢，因為我都會覺得，如果我哋同其他迪士尼比，可能如果偏細嘅話，變咗可能會減低咗嗰個叫做啊旅客重複再翻嚟嘅一個原因。噉我都希望能夠多。
多啲嘢玩，因為啊，我哋亦都大家明白，我哋有一班可能係好中意米奇嘅，但係亦班後生啲嘅可能佢會中意啊Marvels，有啲可能中意Pixar等等，噉我都想聽聽佢大家分享。咁第三啊，第二個問題就係關於啊，譬如話啊，LA啦，洛杉磯有個Downtown Disney㗎，咁會唔會我哋嘅發展嘅時候會唔？
is is driving a lot of business and excitement in the market for us right now, and I think it plays in the timing plays perfectly into our plans for the twentieth anniversary, where we will introduce new products and we'll be sharing that with the the market later in the fall. I think what comes after that.
是新 attraction that we're working on with the shareholders right now. Again, popular IP will be considered with this, and and certainly relevant to guests in in our market. And I think the final phase of this expansion that we're working on right now will be the.
Marvel expansion, we're very excited about it. It's large scale, and will complete the phase one expansion that that started in two thousand and seventeen. All of these will add much needed capacity to our resort, expand its size, as well as I think contribute to you.
Your question with respect to a downtown Disney or retail dining and entertainment expansion, you know certainly merchandise and food and beverage expansion is a key component or capacity is a key component to our guest experience in any of the parks around the world, and we're looking.
冇嘢跟進啊，梁希議員。多謝主席。誒，我哋見到呢個業績咧係好開心嘅。咁不過，與此同時都必須要居安思危，因為我留意到一個好大嘅問題咧，就係我哋二零二三年嗰個構成咧係有百分之六十五都係本地客，而一九年咧百分之六十。
計劃咧。
Mr. Moriarty。
As I think you might expect.
Mr. Moriarty， you know， other attractions， how will they affect you？
超級英雄，which was very highly attended amongst local guests.
另外一方面咧，就第三就係誒出年咧係迪士尼樂園咧開園二十週年，唔知當局咧有冇啲乜嘢？
誒計劃咧係可以即係誒畀翻啲香港市民嘅答謝翻佢哋，因為喺疫情三年咧都係主要谷本地啦，係咪？咁而家誒有錢賺啦，係咪都可以攞少少出嚟畀我哋香港市民都開心下咧？噉樣嚇，唔該主席。
啊，留喺個大嶼山度兩三日去消費嘅，可唔可以都做啲功夫咧？或者譬如話啊，喺澳門係咪啊，賭翻兩手，然後港珠澳大橋，跟住就過嚟香港噉樣贏咗錢又過嚟香港消費，咁幾好啊？係咪？咁所以呢啲方面，我哋係唔可以做啲功夫咧？噉樣樣。
係外地客，即係境外客。咁即係今次嘅增長，主要係來自咧我哋本地嘅客。噉係非常之危險，因為咧明年咧，我哋將會迎嚟全世界最大嘅legoland就喺一河之隔嘅前海。與此同時，明年都會迎嚟全世界最大嘅室內滑雪場。
噉我哋都係睇翻咧喺誒呢個東京佢哋嗰個迪士尼樂園咧，除咗係Disneyland咧，仲係Disney Sea，明年仲要係Disney Sky，即係海陸空。咁所以我哋外圍咧係迎嚟緊一個好大嘅一個衝擊同埋一個競爭。所以今年我哋好，但係明年我哋可以見得到咧。
就係有好大嘅機會，我哋本地嘅客係會流失嘅原因係乜嘢咧？我哋過去北上去消費嘅，可能係成人啦，翻去誒，就係買嘢啊，或者係食嘢啊。咁跟住落嚟，可能就係帶埋小朋友上去去主題樂園㗎啦。咁所以誒，針對住呢啲Legoland或者係室內嘅滑雪場，我想問下誒。
Disney係有啲咩應對嘅方法，同埋點評估佢哋會對我哋嘅園區帶來嘅衝擊咧？會有啲咩誒應對嘅方法咧？同埋誒，我知道第二期我哋而家目前就係收翻翻嚟做我哋自己香港而家其他嘅嘢。咁若然我哋特區政府係畀翻迪士尼你去做嘅話，你會唔會喺未來呢幾年咧？
土地嗰個問題咧，誒其實誒第二期嘅土地政府已經收翻，咁當然到我哋將來誒決定個地方點用嘅時候，我哋會整體去考慮啦。正如我開頭所講，當然我哋即係都會考慮即係迪士尼嘅需要啦，但係我哋整體都係以成個香港即係點樣用笪地最好對。
Madam Chair, thank you. As it relates to local attendance, we're certainly grateful for the record local attendance that we've seen during COVID, but also during fiscal two thousand in twenty three. And you know, I think there is going to be a natural balancing of local attendance.
But as it relates to remaining relevant to local guests, I think the expansion discussions that we've had before certainly will be play a bigger part in that. But you know, moreover, it's you know providing more reasons for local guests to come throughout the year with our special events programs, as well as special promotions. One of the most
popular with local guests, of course, is our Magic Access, which is our annual pass program, which really, you know, provides guests with, you know, a value proposition left to their own imaginations. It is really, it's it's these things, the combination of product, new product expansion, special events, and and ticketing promotion.
that will keep local guests coming back to Hong Kong Disneyland. I also see, you know, a different behaviour in terms of local guests' enthusiasm for all of our brands in each of the special events. You know, most recently we finished the season of Marvel.
有冇嘢跟進周議員？冇啦，好多謝你。跟住周陳少紅議員。哦，多謝啊，主席。
尤其是推廣旅遊城市嘅時候，係點樣將呢一個迪士尼活動結合埋一齊去推廣咧？尤其是係咪會有一個迪士尼月？
嗯，周文港議員，唔該曬主席。其實咧，要揾呢個迪士尼樂園嘅新增長點咧，頭先有議員提到嗰個旅客結構，我哋得出咗結果之後咧，其實都真係要加強翻呢啲誒旅客旅客人數比較少嘅地方嘅一個推廣嘅噉樣樣。咁呢啲方面，唔知你哋有啲咩？
另外一方面咧，其實周邊地區有啲新嘅唔同嘅樂園又好，或者旅遊設施都好，我覺得我哋又唔使太驚嘅。但係我哋真係要做好個一程多站，或者嗰個叫聯遊聯業聯票啊嗰個問題。咁所以咧就其實誒就都想知道誒當局又好，或者誒樂園又好。
點樣同誒大嶼山附近嗰啲景區或者商家啊，啊，包括呢個誒昂坪三六零啊、離島觀光啊，或者未來機場城嗰啲唔同嘅嗰啲誒購物嘅地點啊，做啲折扣啊，啊，做到呢個聯遊聯票啊，所以咧就可以令到嗰啲誒旅客咧可以。
Madam Chair, I spent a little bit of time talking about what we're doing to attract local guests and retain local guests, but we are very much focused on driving tourism not only in mainland China but throughout the the region. And in fact, as I mentioned earlier, we're the top paid attraction in Hong Kong in that regard.
And and really a major driver of tourism to Hong Kong, with fifty two percent of our of our our guests' primary reason to come to Hong Kong, you know, being the visit to our resort. So we're going to continue to focus on that as well, increasing our mix of of tourism and tourists from from outside of Hong Kong.
In bringing those those guests here, as it relates to the 20th anniversary, our focus is is really to celebrate Hong Kong Hong Kong Disneyland and the accomplishments that that we've had over those those 20 years together. Certainly, it will be a combination of new product.
For our guests to enjoy throughout the year, I think some of the product that we haven't had in the resort in a while. We'll also be looking very closely at suggestions like yours, including you know promotions for locals and other markets.
香港迪士尼二零二三年度嘅業績咧，按財政年度嘅就二零二二年十月開始去到二零二三年九月，咁喺頭嘅五個月就因為疫情影響未完全通關啦。咁但係財政年度計嘅全年本地人入場人次係樂樂園開幕以來最。
最高超過四百十萬人次，而非本地人入場人次咧，復甦嘅情況又較整體香港旅客訪港人次為佳。咁呢啲情況實在都值得鼓舞，希望個良好勢頭繼續落去。主席，我有幾個問題想問。第一咧就係誒，大家都比較關心誒迪士尼樂園個。
業績咁而家，今天我睇個業績咧，其實佢顯示咗係二零二三年財政年度誒業績概要。實際上佢哋而家今天就係滯後咗八個月嘅。咁頭先迪士尼公司喺幻燈片度都一至即係講過一次，有一次咧就係話今年一至三月就好多嘅誒業績。
都創下歷史以嚟最最佳嘅創紀錄收入、創紀錄盈利、誒beta、創紀錄淨利潤等等噉樣樣。主席啊，我我其實就都好好想知道誒，既然呢啲咁創紀錄嘅誒業績嘅話，其實係可唔可以提供，直至到去誒你話去唔到五月啦？
主席。
田北辰議員。
唔使諗第二期嗰啲。
就令到整體虧損咧，就減至三點六億。
亦同時係一係列嘅旅遊產品相配套嘅，唔該，主席。
政府點解一直都唔同迪士尼講下數？
錄得九點三億，亦都接近一八一九年嘅十一點三億。
噉啊，扣除咗利息啊、税項啊、折舊嘅盈利，即係EBITDA咧。
我而家咧有一個遺憾同兩個問題，同你分享下嘅。
噉我都鬆一口氣嘅，我呢度咧，恭喜政府同埋整個香港迪士尼團隊。
第二樣嘢咧，就係一個問題，我擔心嘅咧，我就唔擔心地。我知道第一期咧，仲有三成地都未用嘅。
陳議員，你問題太多啦嚇，可以請下迪士尼公司。唔好啦，過咗啦，好多人等。係你，但係問短啲。
局長二二二三年咧總收入五啊七億，係開業以嚟咧第三高，僅次於一八同一九年嘅六十億。
例如，我曾經早前一直提倡，我哋每年嘅專利支付可唔可以同本地嘅虧蝕抵消？
我遺憾嘅咧，就喺香港迪士尼虧蝕三點六億之餘，加畀美國Disney嘅專利費，因為我哋簽咗個不公平條約，仲係高達四點三億。
上邊我哋當然會同迪士尼一齊合作啦。誒，至於話誒會唔會同某一啲嘅城市或者某一啲即係推廣特別推廣某一樣嘢咧？誒，呢個我哋可以再作同迪士尼一齊去傾，睇下點樣一齊加強個工作嘅。
去到三月得唔得咧？咁噉我估咧，佢哋嘅答案就係話：喂，呢啲會唔會係涉及到即係商業嘅誒機密？呢個不適當咁放出嚟。但係我認為，既然呢個業績報告係屬於咩咧？屬於叫做非香港迪士尼經審計嘅財務報表中嘅完整財務業績，我又睇唔到你。
佢就係唔係一個喺香港佢唔係一個上市公司，佢翻翻去母公司誒做一個consolidated經營，唔會睇到香港業務。但係呢個資料重要就讓我哋誒有進一步嘅資料同埋有進一步信心。會唔會直至到誒三月或者甚至乎嚟到五月，係咪？
累計嘅業績係已經扭扭虧為盈咧咁嗱，呢個係對於我哋嘅非常有即係，如果係得嘅話就係好有信心。噉我想了解究竟咩原因底下，你係唔可以提供你嘅數字？哪怕係答一個答案，就係到而家喺你嘅財務報表入邊係咪已經扭虧為盈？我第二個問題咧就係喺。
誒今年業績入邊見到迪士尼嘅吸客能力就十分之好，而且喺迪士尼提交嘅二零二三年財政年度業績概要中第六段咧，佢提到話香港迪士尼具備有利條件，成為香港獨特嘅旅遊目的地之一，推動旅遊業未來增長，係非常之。
又哼張又聲噉，我就想問下局長或同埋迪士尼。其實喺我哋一直以嚟想推動一啲香港城市或者推廣其香港其他嘅旅遊服誒旅遊嘅產品嘅時候，究竟係誒特區政府像楊局長話齋係要同埋迪士尼一齊去做推廣嘅話，尤其。
嗱，好似譬如海洋公園都有十月就Hello Win等等噉，我覺得既然呢個香港嘅一個咁重要嘅一個資產同埋咁重要嘅一個品牌嘅話，係值得香港政府連同迪士尼加把勁去做呢一個推廣，吸引旅客來港嘅意欲，因為我哋唔想佢淨係嚟到香港就淨係參加迪士尼。
都都係主席就誒第一個問題咧。以我所知咧，誒即係誒迪士尼，因為係即係冇公司係美國嘅上市公司啦，所以喺一啲資料嘅提供上邊係有啲限制嘅。咁但係呢個呢個部分，我間請啊誒樂園嗰邊去去講啦。第二部分咧就係喺個宣傳上。
我反而擔心就錢啊！
誒Frozen四廿億已經洗得七七八八啦。
總收入，其他啲唔使你計字，淨係總收入啫。唔該。
二零一七年咧，政府就同美國注資咗一百億。
噉啊！今日咧就流動資產誒，就淨翻十億。
可以即係即係加嗰啲噉樣誒，其他啲誒項目啊，仲有好多維修啊，即係增值。
今日應該寫七七八八啦，因為魔雪奇緣啊寫咗四啊億，一九至二年三年個業績就總共就虧蝕咗三啊二億。
啊！咁最後我想問問Disney嘅，你好難做預測，但係今年頭八個月你嘅總收入幾多？你一定有個數啦，總收入啫。
噉啊，局長答先。我我答先啦。誒，第一個問題，我誒我唔覺得我哋同誒迪士尼簽嗰個係一個誒所謂，即係啊議員所謂嘅不平等條約啦。嗰陣時大家心甘情願，亦都係攞個上嚟立法會。
咁將來任何嘅投資翻新興建，例如正話佢哋講marble要要錢㗎，都要靠每年嘅ebitah累積。噉我都希望每年嘅ebitah都係十億以上啦。不過就噉樣樣加就未有耐。
佢知啦，噉我又唔知你係咪準備再嚟立法會又再誒注資，又再揼多啲錢入去係咪？我睇嗰啲cash flow咧，我就睇唔到你有冇另外一個capital account數住原本嗰一百億未使曬嘅，淨係而家提咧好似二b就係三廿二億同埋。
噉你淨係話畀我聽，你今年頭八個月總收入比起舊年同期個總收入係幾多？我睇個差距咧，我就知道我可以估今年你係賺幾多。你賺係賺緊㗎啦，問題係賺幾多啫。噉我希望你畀到頭八個月實清嘅總。
討論啲細節嘅，咁所以嗰陣時就係大家心甘情願簽落嘅合約。而家我哋以一個合約精神，我哋就要跟足嚟。係咪簽雙倍細冇得嘅？我即係我我講咗畀你聽嗰個睇法啊，即係當然誒每一年嘅暫時有好多原因啦嚇，咁所以唔喺呢度再詳細去講誒。第
第二個問題咧，就係嗰個誒成本。我哋真係誒同迪士尼咧係夾粉大約一百零九億咧，係做一一係列嘅嘅擴展嘅計劃。咁誒而家我哋大約使咗喺嗰一百億度，使咗六十億度咁誒六十億度，但係未使嗰啲錢咧，其實我哋未畀樂園。
咁所以咧，到佢有計劃嘅時候，要擴誒要擴展嘅時候，需要我哋喺嗰原先嗰一百零九億政府嗰部分咧，我哋係到時係會攞出嚟嘅。啊，第三部分我請阿阿雷過咗鐘啦，啊，因為我唔畀得陳議員答，我都唔畀得田議員答嘅，再撳掣啦。
啊！想問就容海欣議員，唔該，主席。誒，我都好開心嘅，見到迪士尼而家嘅成績，尤其是響誒人數啦，同埋誒個收入上面咧係有所提升咧，亦都係有靠一隊專業嘅團隊啦，同埋領導層咧去真係好有心、好落力噉樣去做好誒，亦都見到入邊加咗好多新嘅元素啦，無論響餐飲嘅經。
mega event.
陸總紅議員。
題嘅第二部分，我交畀樂源去講講。
As it relates to giving back, if I may, we are very dedicated and focused on giving back to the community. Not just the 100,000 tickets that we've given away, but our partnership with Make-A-Wish. We work with the Federation of Youth, ethnic minority groups as well as other youth groups here in Hong Kong. Thank you.
經驗啦，誒一啲新嘅園區咧，包括係魔魔雪奇緣啦等等，其實都係帶嚟一啲誒，畀到市民一啲新嘅體驗。亦都知道咧，而家嘅誒旅客嘅成分咧，即係雖然多數係本地市民，但係我哋都希望咧點樣去將園區係打造成為一個畀到誒旅客係多日即係嚟。
到香港係誒幾日嘅經驗，亦都誒即係見到啦，即係誒響唔同嘅報道，亦都有講誒。無論係東京迪士尼同埋香港迪士尼，其實都有好大嘅比較。即係香港係完全完勝到東京迪士尼。雖然咧地方比較細，但係咧所有誒細緻位咧，亦都係做到好，亦都誒好有温度啦，好有熱情啦。
咁所以呢個亦都係我覺得係香港迪士尼嘅一個誒特點，即係我哋點樣去同其他地方有一個競爭嘅一個特點。誒輪候時間短啊，呢啲其實都係我哋優勝嘅地方。當然頭先有議員亦都係關心會唔會係可以做擴充啦，或者係誒響其他地區有迪士尼嘅蹤跡啦。噉我覺。
呢個亦都係可以考慮嘅，即係點樣去將成個嘅好嘅經驗係擴展開去。但係，我想問嘅問題係咧，點樣可以令到去迪士尼嘅誒旅客咧係留多香港幾日，即係畀到佢哋嚟香港多幾日嘅經驗？誒，當然我知道即係各方喺呢方面亦都係落好多功夫啦。即係點誒，無論我哋深
深度遊，無論係綠色遊，當然我哋園區遊其實都係一個諗法。噉，我想先問局長啦，響呢方面點樣去同迪士尼有一個合作，令到嚟嘅旅客咧、嚟訪港旅客咧，係可以留多香港幾日，令到佢哋係多啲誒有唔同嘅經驗。當然響迪士尼入邊有有消費梗係好嘅，但係我哋都希望將。
所有嘅誒經濟效益係可以擴展開去。第二咧，喺誒嚟緊嗰方面咧，即係無論而家頭先聽到啦，誒園區亦都會擴展，Marvel嗰方面又有擴展。噉我想聽翻誒回饋市民嗰方面，即係無論係畀基層市民或者係少數族裔嘅市民，點樣去畀佢哋有有其他嘅誒？
一啲嘅福福利啊，或者係誒回饋社會一方面，可唔可以再講多少少？唔該，主席。誒，都係主席。就第一個問題等我答咧，因為主要佢講緊，譬如點樣留多啲旅客多過一日咧。當然喺樂園度，佢嘅裏邊嘅活動其實你係可以多過一日嘅。咁但係因為佢自己本身亦都有酒店，嚇，亦都有可能有好多唔。
同畀佢夜晚嘅活動等都有噉，但係誒總總體嚟講咧，我哋會同樂園咧誒串連一啲其他嘅活動，包括咗即係譬如我哋有綠色遊啦，我哋亦都有誒香港亦都有好多文化歷史嘅背景啦。我哋譬如可以出西九龍誒西九文化區啦，等等。其實我哋點樣？
喺個宣傳上邊點樣將迪士尼同我哋其他嘅活動串連埋一齊咧？誒呢個我哋一路以嚟都有做，嚟緊我哋會做得更加多添。尤其是藉助即係迪士尼嘅吸引力咧，點樣可以令到吸引去完迪士尼嘅人都會留多一兩日去我哋香港其他景點呢方面，我哋都會去做誒問題。
另外就冇。
營收啊，咁呢方面睇下政府同埋樂園嘅方面有啲咩回應，唔該。
先，田議員問過咧，就話即係專利費咧就好難調啦，因為合約精神。
冇一個正數嘅時候咧，誒，佢嗰個管理費其實係係。
咁個管理費個方面咧，有冇得斟酌嘅空間咧？包括係喺現有嘅協議之下，有冇斟酌嘅空間，或者係？
嚇可變動嗰個嗰部分係冇嘅，誒唔變動嗰個part就仲要仲要畀嚇，咁但係即係佢有好大決，其實係跟嗰個EBITDA，即係同佢嗰個嗰個有有一個規矩喺度。
接近嗰個狀態，咁所以呢個誒似乎就係證明咗咧，喺嚟緊咧，我哋似乎都應該係睇到一個比較接近啲人流管理嘅方面有冇意思？人流管理方面，我哋請啊樂園嗰度講一講，有夠足啦。
邊位答？誒主席，或者我講一講個管理費咧，即係根據我哋同即係個安排咧，誒佢嗰個管理費咧係同個EBITDA係有一個比例嘅，咁誒，所以喺一啲即係譬如係冇誒。
Thank you, Madam Chair. As we look at our guest today, our guest mix as of right now is is not what we saw during fiscal two thousand and three. In fact, our non-local guest is a much higher percentage than we've seen before. And typically, that behaviour is that they do stay at Hong Kong Disneyland on average.
more than one day, and another typical behaviour is after their stay with us, whether in the hotel or visiting the park, they do spend multiple days in Hong Kong, and I think that comes one with the attractiveness of Hong Kong overall, but also our cooperation with the tourism board and various promotions that they have, including.
誒主席，首先啊，即係讚一讚迪士尼過去都有吸納嘅本會嘅一啲意見嘅，包括咧喺舊年咧，我喺呢度都有提出誒迪士尼可唔可以加啲即係本地嘅元素咧？噉我哋最近都收到有啲紀念品咧，迪士尼都頗有即係本地特色嘅，我希望喺呢一方面咧繼續努力去做啦。噉啊，當然。
啦，今年嗰個遊客啊，都係創新高啊，人均消費係創新高。噉啊，Ebitda咧，終於係有錢剩啦。噉啊，雖然咧嗰個淨虧損咧仍然有三點五億，咁但係都係一個大幅嘅改善嚟嘅。咁但係咧都有個誒幸福嘅煩惱啊，主席。噉啊，人多入。
長咧，我最近我仔咧上個星期咧就同我講佢即係就嚟放暑假咧，有半日假噉啊，去迪士尼啦。下晝噉啊，好快就翻屋企。我問佢：喂，做乜咁快翻屋企啊？嚇！我翻工嘅時候啊，我誒好多人啊，多人都排好耐都冇嘢玩啊，噉樣嗱。噉啊，幸福嘅煩惱咧就係即係睇下迪士尼咧，即係。
即係你遊客咁多咧，會唔會喺個空間啊，同埋嗰個人潮嘅管理咧，有啲更加優化嘅措施？咁當然啦，研究下即係即係長遠去研究會唔會擴大個園區咧？但係短期之內喺嗰個即係遊人嘅體驗嘅方面，因為如果人太多咧，你畀人講嚟幾次，喂太多人咧，下次唔好去啦，即係排到好鬼耐都冇有。
玩嘅噉你咧下一水咧就可能冇咁多人㗎啦。噉啊，另外一個咧就係嗰個遊客嘅比例咧都係偏少嘅，得三分之一係遊客，三分之二咧係本地人。點樣做好咧？即係遊客嘅呢方面嘅宣傳咧，我覺得都係要增加啲努力。咁點樣鼓勵即係園區嘅管理層？
即係加強我努力啊，或者動多啲心思腦筋嗰方面咧。嗱，誒迪士尼咧就係香港迪士尼就合營公司啦，就政府又唔係二管權嘅。咁但係咧由誒迪士尼管理公司，即係美國直屬嘅去管理，噉啊會收取管理費同埋專利費嘅。噉啊，頭。
將來有冇一個檢討協議嘅時間或者係機制？誒，將佢個管理費甚至乎誒管理層嘅薪酬花紅啊，同嗰個樂園嘅表現係掛鈎，咁令到咧樂園咧有更加積極嘅措施咧去吸引遊客啊，或者係改善嗰個營。
謝謝。
或者我請樂源。好啊，嚇，Mr. Moriarty。
推出嘅優惠咧，吸引更多嘅遊客嚟Disney。
guest in into Hong Kong when we are
the the chart that we showed earlier where we're outpacing the overall tourism market here in Hong Kong.
咁咧，其中咧，我哋國泰航空可唔可以發揮更大嘅作用咧？作為東主嘅嗰個航空公司嘅作用，咁咧包括咧多啲推動嘅嗰個多啲中轉客嚟誒香港咧，園區旅遊咧，唔該。
等下一個，想問啊，再撳掣啦，因為我要公平啲，所有人咧一視同仁啊嚇。嚴光議員都等咗好耐啦，奇緣。好多謝主席誒，我本人咧對於Disney嘅呢兩年嘅表現咧係充分肯定嘅誒。
哦，有關於我，我或者講講少少嗰個誒人數，即係話好多議員都講咧，即係話誒二零二零二三年咧，嗰個旅客即係本地客同非本地客嗰個比例咧，就誒本地客好似多過非本地客好多。其實呢個就係如果我哋分開上半年同下半年。
睇咧，正話喺個slide度都有一張咧。其實下半年咧，我哋嗰個非本地客咧，其實已經超過一半，翻翻去百分之五啊五。本地客四啊五。咁所以其實你見到咧，因為一通咗關之後咧，其實已經見到翻翻去，即係喺疫情之前。
咁咧，啱啱國長都提過嗰個本地嘅遊客咧，舊年誒三高啦，四百一十萬，噉啊，佔咗百分之六十四啦。咁咧，我第一個問題咧問一問咧，如果係收入方面嘅佔比係幾多？即係本地嘅誒四百一十萬嘅收入咧，佔咗成體收入嘅幾多？係咪都係相約嘅？
百分之六幾咧嚇。第二個問題咧係誒，除咗吸引咧內地遊客，咁咧東南亞亞洲國家嘅遊客都係重要嘅客源地啦嚇。咁咧境外遊客咧嚟香港最大嘅成本應該都係誒機飛㗎啦誒機票。咁咧請問園區咧如何加大同航空公司嘅合作，能夠推出咧pack？
Thank you, Madam Chair. You know, as it relates to our overall mix, certainly we are grateful for the very strong local business. But our focus really is about bringing tourists into to Hong Kong, especially during those other holiday periods. When we when we look at our
really what that means is that the promotional efforts that we've had in Southeast Asia and in mainland China are driving a higher penetration to Hong Kong Disneyland than that we've seen in the past. That is to say that our promotional efforts in Southeast Asia are relatively more effective than we have been historically.
which is I think a sign of the strong effort that that we've had there. When we look at partnerships with airlines, Cathay Pacific as one example, we're really focused on multi-channel strategy, including airlines, to tap into any market opportunity to bring.
I think the the the last question that you had was was around the overall mix of our revenue. I think one of the things that we have seen is that overall guest spending has gone up. It's gone up relatively equally to what we have seen historically as.
We've introduced new pricing tiers, but also we've seen increases in merchandise and food and food and beverage sales, as well as introducing new product lines like Disney's Premier Access, a pay for privilege product which.
是very popular with tourists and when we add all of these things together our overall value for money scores with our guests remains very high 90% but we've also seen increases in our overall guest satisfaction as well and while it is a happy problem that we're crowded on days we're also
嗯，有冇跟著？
噉啊！呢方面我都想問下局長咧，其實。
誒呢個嘅星夢光影之旅咧，咁其實～
客人噉啊，有幾多percent係不過嘢嘅？
畀樂園嗰邊。O.K. 我會補翻時間，李耀議員，Mr. Moriarty。
即係喺嗰個園區裏邊咧，即係入園嘅。
埋夜間嘅餐飲，睇埋個show先至離離場。咁其實即係等於係我哋講緊係將迪士尼嘅夜經濟係帶動咗。
冇跟進，冇，嗯，OK。噉啊，下一位姚柏良議員，誒，都係主席，主席，我都係非常之高興睇到迪士尼有咁好嘅業績，噉啊，亦都係即係為香港嘅旅遊業，即係吸引旅客嚟香港咧，發揮咗一定嘅作用。噉啊，誒，我都有幾個問題想問嘅，其實就。
working very hard on making sure that we manage seasonality with other promotions like our Magic Access, which makes it more accessible, especially to local guests as well as guests from Shenzhen or the Greater Bay Area to come during shoulder periods where it might not be as as busy.
咁有幾多percent係有過嘢嘅？我想了解喺呢方面，因為過嘢嘅當然誒有幾多係住喺迪士尼入邊噉，大家會知道啦。噉就唔知有冇掌握到即係唔過嘢嘅旅客嘅比例有幾多？咁呢度我想了解少少數據嘅啫。咁但係我自己都睇到即係迪士尼即係成功嘅經驗咧，其實我都睇到係一個即係。
對一個喺我話喺個應變求變同埋產品創新嗰方面，我覺得係呢個係做得相當之好嘅。咁尤其是係響嗰個疫情期間咧，即係推出呢個迪士尼嘅星夢光影之旅咧，我成日都講，即係係將係成功將客人咧留喺園裏邊嘅時間延長咗，同埋咧即係帶動。
政府會唔會考慮下，即係有冇會唔會有啲藉口、值得參考嘅地方？我哋而家要打造一個即係為港嘅誒環翠榮香港呢個新版本嘅巨吸引力嘅，咁呢方面係咪有冇啲可以值得借鏡嘅地方？咁另外嚟講咧，誒睇到其實迪士尼咧，響嗰個文體類嘅融合嗰方面咧。
都做咗啲實踐嘅，噉我覺得都非非常之成功嘅。好似呢個嘅誒管絃樂團啦、芭蕾舞蹈團啦，我哋香港嘅本本地嘅著名嘅呢個文化嘅I P嚟嘅，咁亦都喺園裏邊有好好嘅合作，同時間亦都係將一個誒園區入邊嘅跑步嘅運動咧，亦都結合。
埋落去噉，其實我覺得呢方面可以能夠再加強做多啲，去做一個引領示範嘅作用，希望能夠推動我哋香港個文體類嘅融合，可以能夠即係加加速發展。同時嚟講，誒，我亦都係希望非常之期望咧。其實香港迪士尼閃耀旅遊業呢個呢個功能咧，可以。
The last question that you had.
Thank you, thank you。啊，李維宏業。
講迪士尼咧，將以用誒作為一個新期、新一期個擴建，所以呢三條問題，唔該曬。
being overnight vacation arrivals. When we look at the hotels, we see a lot of
Please continue. I can give you a few more minutes. Okay, thank you. So, the if I could get a clarification on the last question, it was.
similar behaviour there guests are coming overnight and staying with us obviously majority of our hotel guests are from outside of of Hong Kong right now which is very different than during COVID.
可以點樣真係可以進一步發揮咧？頭先我哋好多議員都講緊，即係嗱誒迪士尼有好嘅業績，我哋當然好高興。但係點樣利用好香港呢個迪士尼呢呢呢張咁亮麗嘅名片，去帶動到我哋整體旅遊業嘅復甦，以致到誒周邊大嶼山又好，或者我哋其他市區。
去嘅一啲其他嘅誒景點啊，或者唔同嘅旅遊產業鏈裏邊嘅唔同嘅誒組合，都能夠能夠受惠到呢個即係誒誒吸引旅客嚟呢方面，可能我令到佢哋同時間有唔同嘅產品都能夠相互帶動，令到大家係整體能夠得益，整體能夠發揮到個效應。嚇唔該，主席。
好多問題，暫停一停，因為我哋呢個會應該五點四廿五分完嘅，噉我而家將時間延長十五分鐘到六點，嚇，噉啊邊位答先？誒主席，我我好快講一句就係誒，我哋環彩榮香港啦，我哋會考慮周邊即係所有地方我哋嘅成功經驗去諗嘅，其實如果交畀。
Madam Chair, according to the Hong Kong Tourism Board, we've seen an increase in the percentage of overnight vacation arrivals into Hong Kong as compared to two thousand and eighteen levels. You know, versus the same day arrivals, we're seeing a similar phenomena there among our our guests.
Actually, I think the secretary. Oh, I'm sorry. As it relates to working with people on land, tell sorry. You know, I think like Hong Kong, we have a lot of good materials, and Disney has a global brand that will help further put Hong Kong on the world's map. I think together we can work at really helping better Hong Kong tourism. We need to.
Continue to highlight the strategic benefits of Hong Kong Disneyland being an international brand in an international city like Hong Kong. I think that that will help attract families to Hong Kong, as well as a lot of good things to attract them, like the other attractions on on Lantau as well.
啊！多謝主席。今日聽到誒迪士尼樂園度假區最新嘅進展報告咧，都好多正面嘅訊息啦。咁無論係嗰個樂園總入場人次、誒賓客嘅人均消費都上升啦，噉啊總收入亦都係誒上升。噉啊誒二零二三年整體有呢個盈利都係好好嘅。噉啊有幾個跟進問題想了。
解多少少啦。噉啊，第一就係誒討論文件入邊有提及到迪士尼嗰個香港迪士尼嗰個誒淨融資支出咧，喺誒由二零二二年財政年度嘅三千三百萬元咧，誒急誒急增至到八千二百萬港元嘅，咁嗰個增幅都達到一點五倍。啊，咁所以。
嗯。
Mr. Moriarty。
其餘嘅時間，我交畀誒樂源去答嚇。Mr. Moriarty。
誒有冇跟進？冇冇其他跟進。跟住周浩鼎議員。
Like they should have confidence in it too, as as a key driver to tourism in Hong Kong over the next few years.
But I think I need to assert this sort of opinion because I'm very much concerned about the fierce competition, the upcoming fierce competition. Yeah, that's all. Thank you.
It relates to capacity limits. We're always focused on making sure that we have a great guest experience for all of our guests. We have several products, especially for school groups that are half-day in nature, that help do this as well. And we'll certainly take your advice under consideration. Thank you.
喺呢方面，想誒都知道，主要係因為嗰個利利率嗰個上升所致啦。所以未來咧誒，想聽少少從財政角度咧，香港迪士尼有冇啲咩措施咧，去控制呢個誒淨融資支出嘅增加？噉啊，隨著嗰個誒利率而家相對嚟講比較高企嘅情況。咁第二個問題都想問咧，就都。
都我都有聽過一啲意見，就我知道迪士尼本身都有好多唔同嘅誒飛可以買嘅，譬如話一啲連飛啊，或者係一次性嘅。噉啊誒，亦都有啲意見認為，如果譬如話誒，我唔知道每一日嗰個唔同時段嗰個誒誒容容容納到幾多人啦，但係會唔會有一啲類型嘅飛咧，係譬如話係針對一啲誒夜晚。
嚟嘅或者唔同時段咁有啲人可能誒，如果夜晚唔係咁忙嘅，佢哋可以嚟食飯咁玩一陣噉啊，睇埋煙花咁變咗啲票價又可以有少少折扣咧。噉你其實又可以揾到多少少即係另外一種誒嘅嘅旅客啊，或者另外一種人嚟嚟參參加。咁第三同埋最後一條問題咧就。
啊！即係好多啲議員都有關注關於呢個擴建同埋發展嘅計劃啦。咁誒，具體少少啦。噉我都係想誒瞭解下，即係為咗進一步去增加呢個香港迪士尼嗰個樂園嘅設施咧，即係提誒提升呢個吸引力，政府會唔會考慮咧？喺將呢個竹篙灣誒興建呢個方艙醫院嗰個用地啊，即係重新去同香。
局長答先啦。誒土地正話都講咗㗎啦，我哋都係要考考慮整體嘅利益啦。當然即係迪士尼對成個香港經濟嘅嘅貢獻啦，同埋即係對旅遊業嘅貢獻，呢個我哋一定會考慮嘅。咁誒，所以土地嗰度我哋會作一個長遠嘅考慮咧。暫時即係冇冇乜嘢可以暫時喺度補充。
Madam Chair, as it relates to the increase in the financing expenses, certainly interest rates played a big role in that. Very proud to say that the revolving revolver facility has been completely paid off in December, which will result in lower financing expenses going forward. As a
哦，thank you. I think I'm very impressed by your performance this year, and I think you did quite well on the penetration rate as to the tourist. But I'm quite concerned about the future competition with Zhangjia, because in light of the fierce competition, you know the new entertainment facilities to be built in Zhangjia to be to be.
opened in Shanghai. What is the plan for Disneyland on any expansion plan, any new rides? I think you need these sort stuff to attract tourists, especially international visitors. So this is my opinion. I know that I do know that you have already provided your answer.
So as we look at the the attractions that we've added in the in the past few years, when no one else was investing in attractions, you know, frankly around around the world, popular intellectual property drawing with international appeal, drawing people to Hong Kong, Moana, Moana, Marvel.
嗯。
啊，邊位可以答？
主席，好多謝你。
positive feedback as well.
乜嘢咧？即係內地人一般認為港迪好過上迪嘅。
嘢冇跟冇跟就好啦，跟住我有條比較簡單問題問阿局長嘅啫。
誒噉，我冇嘢問咧。而家有兩位誒議員咧，係第二次提問嘅。噉我哋有足夠時間，田議員同陳少雄議員每人三分鐘。
限制嘅，即係佢隔離起嘅嘢咧，就要配合園景嘅嚇。噉係點乜嘢可以喺嗰度起咧？你認為嚇？
或者我請樂園啦。Madam Chair，I think those questions are best left for the guest. I think Hong Kong Disneyland has a unique position in place and and is a uniquely different experience than Shanghai, which is also a very fine place to visit.
I think we are uniquely Hong Kong in that way, and I think we can help drive that perception among tourists into Hong Kong, as well as being extremely relevant to family guests throughout the year. Okay, thank you. You are very protective of Shanghai Disneyland.
The Newcastle of Magical Dreams in the Nighttime Show has really been a game changer for us, leveraging all the popular IP. But the world of Frozen, as the number one Disney brand in Asia and all of our key markets, has certainly made a big difference. And so, those international brands.
The popularity in all of our key markets are designed for one thing: bringing people into Hong Kong. And as you look at the lineup that we have going forward, clearly those elements are going to be embedded into our twenty-th anniversary celebration and everything that we do within that, really inviting people to Hong Kong Disneyland for the first time.
As we look at the Marvel expansion, Marvel has global appeal. Continued investment and support, not only in with Disney Plus in our key markets, but also theatrically, is going to provide a lot of international appeal, drawing people in, and all.
also as I mentioned earlier we're working on an attraction in between the 20th anniversary and Marvel again designed to bring tourists into Hong Kong when you look at our competition whether Shenzhen or elsewhere it's hard to say that anyone has a lineup quite as strong as Hong Kong Disneyland.
against the competition in terms of of the product, and it's important to remember that all of the things that we have open today, a lot of our key markets, the guests haven't even visited Hong Kong yet, so it's going to be brand new for them as well. I'm very confident in the in the lineup that we have, and I hope that that people feel.
誒喺迪士尼隔離嗰六十公頃地咧，即係我知道迪士尼完嗰個right of first refusal啊，即係優先使用權咧個時限已經過咗啦，所以個土地就屬於政府啦。咁但係好似你哋同迪士尼、港府同迪士尼嘅協議咧，都有啲限。
會會將來點樣咧？會點限制你嗰個土地使用咧？有咩諗法咧？政府嚟嘅誒，多謝主席。就誒，或者我間睇下專員可唔可以答到嗰個地嗰個實際可以做到啲乜？但係係的確有個限制嘅誒。整體嗰個背後嗰個原則咧，都係。
誒唔會即係影響到成個樂園佢嗰個誒周圍作為一個樂園嗰個氣氛，即係譬如好簡單，唔會起好多高樓大廈喺側邊遮住佢個景觀嗰嗰類。咁誒容許啲誒乜嘢可以做咧？如果我呢度同事未必達到啊，我會後補。
補補充翻畀大家嚇。嗯，跟住我想問啊，Mr. Moriarty咧就誒小紅書咧就成日每日都有嘅，就話誒港迪嘅慘狀，即係話好多人排隊噉啊。佢哋就話港迪比上迪好嘅嚇，點解咧？你哋認為你哋嘅成功要素啊？
嗯。
Surely you can share that, right?
我都係重複翻個三個問題啦。
噉我哋一路投資落去，個結構就一路會高企不下。
我想了解下係咪冇得傾嘅？永遠永遠都係咁㗎啦！呢個第一個問題啫。
三個啫。係局長主席，我或者請誒樂園答先咧，因為第一輪我答曬啲時間，我請樂園答先。好啊，Mr. Moriarty。
今日咧嗰個專利費咧就係同總收入硬掛掛鈎嘅，管理費咧就同EBT硬掛掛鈎嘅。
咁嗰兩樣嘢咧都唔可以確保我哋整體會唔會有盈利，因為仲要減我哋嗰啲投資，投資就產生嗰啲折舊啊噉。
競爭嘅時候，誒，你正話好多言提過深圳嚟緊好多唔同嘅建設嘅時候，嗰個嗰個I P本身就係佢一個強項，咁所以作為一個即係誒保障咧，我覺得喺嗰個專利費度，我哋其實真係應該要畀嚇。
咁所以我之前就問呢個係咪誒硬骨嘅掛鈎係咪千秋萬世都冇得去傾？因為港鐵加價，政府都五年檢討一次啦。我依家二十年咯，二十年都唔可以攞出嚟傾傾。
It is it is very interesting now as we as we see social media shaping opinions in in the market. That is an important piece of of how we get our our message out there. It is flattering to get feedback like that, and I know that Shanghai gets feedback is.
As it relates to our uniqueness, I think that as I mentioned earlier, Hong Kong Disneyland has a very special place in Hong Kong in demonstrating its international flavour and international appeal to consumers who want that, which is different than frankly any other park, any other Disney park in the world.
第二個問題咧，我好高興聽到你哋話，原來嗰一百億咧未使曬嘅，使咗一缺嘅啫，仲有四廿億仲可以抌落去Marvel啊、Expansion啊噉樣樣，噉就唔係反映喺個流動資產嗰個十億嗰度。噉我希望第日啲文件可以即係對我。
嚟講，嗰樣嘢係重中之重。啊，希望你哋即係即係聽一聽。第三咧就Mr.Moriarty，the first eight months of total gate receipt，total income，certainly you will have that。Can you just share with me the first eight months total revenue versus last year's the first eight months?
Madam Chair, as I mentioned earlier, Q1 of 2024 was a record quarter for us of all time, revenue, EBITDA and profit. As it relates to information going beyond that, I'm not able to share that right now, but I look forward to sharing that with the panel in our next.
你冇得 interest。
Alright. Okay.冇第啲問題。
the supplement, I mean, on the on the profit.
I think, Madam Chair, I think that's a question that we would have to follow up with Secretary.
啲叫中期業績報告嘅話，假如佢出咗嚟，咪可以提。誒，我我應承議員，如果有一啲公開資料係做得到嘅，我哋會會畀意見。
The other debt that we have, the other shareholder loan that we have on the balance sheet for the hotel. Could you provide the supplementary information after this panel meeting on paper? Is it is it possible? And if it is not, what's the reason why?
淨 profit as well as the the net profit that you claim that you have recorded record high in the first quarter, so I understand that you don't have the information in hand. That I understand, but could you provide this supplementary information later?
起住宅樓宇啊，呢啲就唔可以。噉我哋會後可以畀個詳細啲個表嘅嚇。好嘅，好嘅，多謝你。啊，多謝顧長。Thank you, Mr. Moriarty. I join my colleagues in congratulating Hong Kong Disney for the stellar performance. Keep up the good work. 啊，多謝。
所以我非常 optimistic about our profitability， you know going forward， especially you know this late this late in the year， and certainly look forward to sharing those results with the panel in next year's session， as as we look at the interest rate for
喺我哋嘅會議室。主席或者我講一講，即係誒有關於佢嗰個專利費同埋嗰個管理費。管理費其實改過嘅，即係喺二零零九年嘅時候，我哋曾經作過一啲調整。而家咧就變咗完全跟嗰個EBDA係掛鈎嘅，即係話如果佢。
佢誒repeater係冇，即係係一個負數嘅時候，噉就唔會有一個管理費。咁誒，所以唔會話唔改得。不過咧喺個專利費度咧，誒的確大家要睇得到咧，即係樂園本身嗰個強項其實就喺個I.P.度，亦都係點樣可以面對其他地方嘅。
夠鐘啦，跟住就陳少雄議員三分鐘。多謝主席。主席，我都係跟正翻頭先我問嘅問題未答嘅，就可否誒迪士尼公司提供二零二三年十月至二零二四年三月嘅業績概要咧？咁頭先啊，迪士尼公司就話而家冇資料喺度，就話係等下一個。
Panel先要提供啦，咁其實係我可可唔可以而家講唔有冇資料冇問題啦？就會後可唔可以提供下咧？因為我所關心嘅地方就係究竟即係喺而家你嘅預估未來嘅業績底下咧，就嗰個誒即係咪有機會扭虧為盈？我第二個問題想問咧，就係迪士尼公司喺二零二三年。
財政年度初，即係二零二二年十月，就曾經向華特迪士尼公司一間附屬公司提取十八億港元嘅信貸款項，並喺二零二三年十二月全數償還。嗱，我想誒瞭解下就有關貸款嘅利息支出係幾多啫？兩個問題唔該。請迪士尼公司。Mr. Moriarty。
Thank you, Madam Chair. As it relates to our overall profit position right now, I think as I mentioned earlier, we were profitable in calendar two thousand and twenty-three, and we had a record quarter in Q one, and that momentum and profitability continues.
the the revolving credit facility, it's based on it's a floating plus fixed basis. It's HIBOR plus one twenty five, one hundred and twenty five basis points, which is which is lower in fact than.
O.K.主主席啊，或者打答，以我所知咧，誒，因為美國上市公司嘅問題咧，呢啲數字我哋誒應該係唔會即係喺佢正式公佈之前咧，誒，我哋係唔唔適宜或者係唔唔可以將佢disclose嘅嚇。我明白，如果假如佢有啲。
唔該，謝謝。
OK。
十月見啦。
誒，下次會議。
十月喎，係十月嘅十月啊！
其他事項冇其他事項。下次會議係幾時？
好，好，嗯，O K啊啊！主席啊，可唔可以嘥多少少時間講一講嗰個誒土地限制嗰個？我哋揾到少少資料好快。阿阿主席，其實好簡單，嗰個土地限制個限制性契約裡面咧，誒定明咧有關嘅用途，只有商業、休憩、體育同埋文化嘅用途，即係話愛嚟。